<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kssgarcia</title>
    <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kssgarcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 11:48:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kssgarcia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BESO optimzation code</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/beso/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will be present a python code for ESO optimization method.
Problem statement Let us consider a cantilever beam with a vertical force of 10kN, dimensions 20x10 meters, young module of 206.8 GPa and Poisson&amp;rsquo;s ratio 0.28 figure 1 $RR=0.01$, $ERR=0.005$.
Figure 1. Beams&amp;rsquo;s diagram. First, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following steps to do algorithm:
Discretize the domain and assign the initial property, 0 or 1, for each element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESO optimization code.</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/how_eso/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/how_eso/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will be present a python code for ESO optimization method.
Problem statement Let us consider a cantilever beam with a vertical force of 10kN, dimensions 20x10 meters, young module of 206.8 GPa and Poisson&amp;rsquo;s ratio 0.28 figure 1 $RR=0.01$, $ER=0.005$.
Figure 1. Beams&amp;rsquo;s diagram. First, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following steps to do algorithm:
Discretization of the model in finite elements Perform the finite element analysis of the structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stiff bases ESO optimization code</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/stiff_eso/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/stiff_eso/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will be present a python code for ESO optimization method.
Problem statement Let us consider a cantilever beam with a vertical force of 10kN, dimensions 20x10 meters, young module of 206.8 GPa and Poisson&amp;rsquo;s ratio 0.28 figure 1 $RR=0.01$, $ER=0.005$.
Figure 1. Beams&amp;rsquo;s diagram. First, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following steps to do algorithm:
Discretization of the model in finite elements Perform the finite element analysis of the structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIMP Method for Topology Optimization</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/simp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/simp/</guid>
      <description>This method has been shown to be used in a large number of problems, since it is computationally efficient and simple to implement. Unlike BESO ESO/BESO this method uses a soft-kill criterion, that is, the elements are not completely eliminated, they are only reduces the elastic modulus or one of the dimensional characteristics. This criterion is implemented since the complete removal of elements can result in theoretical difficulties.
The problem presented seeks to minimize the minimum compliance of the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESO/BESO</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/eso_beso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/eso_beso/</guid>
      <description>The ESO (evolutionary structural optimization) and BESO (bi-directional evolutionary structural optimization) methods are methods with hard-kill optimization criteria, that is, they can eliminate material and this causes the domain to be modified.
The ESO method consists of the simple concept of removing material that is inefficient. This is done by calculating the stresses in the entire model and eliminating the elements with low values.
Optimization by level of stress For this, the stress level of each element is calculated and compared with criteria defined as rejection criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approach to structural optimization.</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/approximation-to-optimization-structural/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/approximation-to-optimization-structural/</guid>
      <description>This post will talk about structural optimization from a more general point of view, with the aim of strengthening the bases for future applications.
To understand in a simple way the background of structural optimization it is a good idea to separate the two terms and take the definition of each. Optimization consists of doing things better and a structure can be understood as an assembly of material that has the purpose of supporting loading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2023</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/project-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/project-2023/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will talk about the project which I will be working approximate one year. The project is about structural optimization using machine learning. The general objetive is design microstructures of hybrids materials using structural optimization.
With advances in the manufacturing technology of microstructures of materials, the interest has increased around material simulation and optimization. One idea that is had with the arrival of new technologies is the design and manufacture of microstructures for desired properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install OneDriver Linux</title>
      <link>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/install-onedriver-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 11:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kssgarcia.github.io/posts/install-onedriver-linux/</guid>
      <description>This post is an installation&amp;rsquo;s guide for OneDriver on Ubuntu or Debian distributions.
Almost my entire life I have used a computer with Windows operating system, some mouth ago I decide to try Linux operating system, just for curiosity, so I made a dual boot in my laptop giving me the possibility to use Linux and Windows, I decided to make this because there are some programs which aren&amp;rsquo;t available on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
